import { Category } from 'src/app/interfaces/category.interface';

export default {
  name: 'Алфавит (кириллица)',
  cards: [
    {
      question: 'A а',
      answer:  '[a]',
    },
    {
      question: 'Б б',
      answer:  '[б]',
    },
    {
      question: 'В в',
      answer:  '[в]',
    },
    {
      question: 'Г г',
      answer:  '[г]',
    },
    {
      question: 'Д д',
      answer:  '[д]',
    },
    {
      question: 'Ђ ђ',
      answer:  'мягкое [дж]  мягкая д и как бы мягкая ж',
    },
    {
      question: 'Е е',
      answer:  '[э]',
    },
    {
      question: 'Ж ж',
      answer:  '[ж]',
    },
    {
      question: 'З з',
      answer:  '[з]',
    },
    {
      question: 'И и',
      answer:  '[и]',
    },
    {
      question: 'Ј ј',
      answer:  '[й]',
    },
    {
      question: 'К к',
      answer:  '[к]',
    },
    {
      question: 'Л л',
      answer:  '[л]',
    },
    {
      question: 'Љ љ',
      answer:  '[ль]',
    },
    {
      question: 'М м',
      answer:  '[м]',
    },
    {
      question: 'Н н',
      answer:  '[н]',
    },
    {
      question: 'Њ њ',
      answer:  '[нь]',
    },
    {
      question: 'О о',
      answer:  '[о]',
    },
    {
      question: 'П п',
      answer:  '[п]',
    },
    {
      question: 'Р р',
      answer:  '[р]',
    },
    {
      question: 'С с',
      answer:  '[с]',
    },
    {
      question: 'Т т',
      answer:  '[т]',
    },
    {
      question: 'Ћ ћ',
      answer:  'мягкое [ч]',
    },
    {
      question: 'У у',
      answer:  '[у]',
    },
    {
      question: 'Ф ф',
      answer:  '[ф]',
    },
    {
      question: 'Х х',
      answer:  '[х]',
    },
    {
      question: 'Ц ц',
      answer:  '[ц]',
    },
    {
      question: 'Ч ч',
      answer:  'твёрдое [ч] как бы между ТШ',
    },
    {
      question: 'Џ џ',
      answer:  'твёрдое [дж] (как в слове джем)',
    },
    {
      question: 'Ш ш',
      answer:  '[ш]',
    },
  ]
} as Category;

